### **ALIAKSEI RAVENKA**

Phone: +375 29 342 84 62 4

Email: aliakseiravenka@gmail.com

**Skype:** alexei\_r.1

Linkedin: linkedin /in /aliaksei-ravenka



### **Objective**

Intern QA Manual

#### Skills

- English Proficiency: Upper-Intermediate (B2)
- Working with a large amount of information and its structuring
- Programming languages: SQL
- API testing: Postman
- Load testing tool: JMeter
- Version control system: Git

### **Summary**

For the last eight years, I have worked as a Lead certification engineer of heavy-duty vehicles. That gave me great experience in the analysis of requirements for products and finding inconsistencies between requirements and products. I want to develop in the field of quality.

### Work experience

# 09.2021-11.2021 - Trainee, Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy).

Project description: training testing of the web application <a href="www.likar.info">www.likar.info</a>, development of a testing plan and strategy, and control of their implementation, development of a checklist, execution of testing, introduction of defects into Jira. Development of a Test Result Report.

## 10.2013–03.2022 – Lead Certification Engineer, Joint-stock company "Minsk automobile plant".

Main responsibilities: analysis of requirements, development of a test plan of testing vehicles and technical descriptions for vehicles in Russian and English, analysis of test results.

Achievements: The all needed certificates get on time. Always.

### 06.2001-10.2013 - Certification Engineer, Joint-stock company "Minsk automobile plant".

Main responsibilities: analysis of requirements, preparation of technical descriptions for vehicles in Russian and English.

Achievements: I solved tasks that more experienced employees could not manage.

### **Education**

### 09.2021–11.2021 – Educational Center for Programming and High Tech (IT-Academy)

Course: "Software functional testing"

### 09.1997-06.2001 - Belarusian National Technical University

Specialization: Vehicles

Qualification: Mechanical Engineer